JOSHUA CLANCY

Web Developer

PROFILE

Web Developer and Former Educator

I can handle multiple tasks daily while working under pressure.

I'm used to setting and achieving goals by working with a team.

I am always willing to learn something new including programming languages.

Github projects showcasing both backend and frontend web development available.

I have work experience in several other fields upon request.

CONTACT

214-518-3948

joshuamichael.clancy@gmail.com

https://pbnjson.github.io/Updated-Portfolio/dist/index.html

EDUCATION

TEXAS A&M - COMMERCE (grad. 2007)

Bachelor of Science Major in Psychology / Major in Spanish

SMU Software Engineer (grad. 2022)

Full Stack Web Development – JavaScript w/ React

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mesquite ISD - Bilingual Education

2007-2014

From 2007-2014 I taught in a bilingual Spanish classroom, 1st and 2nd grade.

Mesquite ISD – General Education

2014-Current

I taught in a monolingual – English – classroom grades 1^{st} – 3^{rd} . During my teaching career I have held many positions within the school.

Autoglass Express Owner

2021-Current

Owner of an auto glass installation company, registered.

SKILLSET

- ES5 ES9 JavaScript
- HTML/CSS including SASS
- Node.js
- Various npm libraries (sequelize, express, etc.)
- jQuery
- Promised based API Calls, 3rd party and in-house
- Unit Testing with jest
- MySql and NoSql with Mongo DB
- React.js
- ** Learning is my hobby. Currently studying data visualization, Ethereum based blockchain and smart contracts.